Cash is king, or so they say.
人们常说，现金为王。
In one form or another, human beings have been carrying around money for hundreds of years.
数百年来，人类一直以这样或那样的形式使用货币。
Metal was first coined into cash between 700 and 600 BC by the Lydians, and banknotes have been in circulation since their first use in China around 1000 AD.
公元前700至600年间，吕底亚人率先将金属铸造成钱币；而纸币则于公元1000年左右在中国首次出现，并自此开始流通。
These days, though, habits have changed.
但如今，人们的支付习惯已经发生了改变。
Modern technology means that while money is still widely used, it's more likely to be a digital transaction than a wad of notes and a handful of shrapnel.
现代技术的发展意味着，虽然货币仍被广泛使用，但相比一沓纸币和一把硬币，人们更倾向于选择数字交易的方式。
If cash is king, then it may eventually be dethroned.
如果说现金曾是王者，那么它或许终将走下王座。
In the UK, the use of tangible currency is in decline.
在英国，实体货币的使用量正在下降。
In 2017, the banking trade body UK Finance reported a 15% fall in the use of ready money.
2017年，银行业协会英国金融城曾报告称，现金的使用量下降了15%。
Since their first use, debit card payments have given cash a run for its money.
自借记卡问世以来，其支付方式就对现金的地位构成了有力挑战。
Last year, for the first time ever, the use of debit cards and contactless payments became the most popular way to stump up.
去年，借记卡和非接触式支付首次成为最主流的付款方式。
In fact, if trends continue, the use of cold hard cash, would end by 2026, says the report.
该报告还指出，事实上，如果这种趋势持续下去，现金的使用或将在2026年彻底终结。
For businesses, the smart money is on not taking cash. By doing so, they are in the money.
对商家而言，不收取现金才是明智之举，这样做能让他们盈利颇丰。
For example, the Boot pub in Freston opened last year as a cashless pub.
例如，弗雷斯顿的布特酒吧去年开业时就定位为无现金酒吧。
In a BBC article, its owner Mike Keen lists several advantages, including a quicker speed of service, lower insurance premiums since no cash is kept on site, and a saving in time as he needn't cash up each day nor make a deposit in the bank several times each week.
在英国广播公司的一篇报道中，酒吧老板迈克·基恩列举了无现金经营的诸多好处，包括服务效率更高、因店内不存放现金而降低了保险费用，同时也节省了时间——他不必再每天结算现金，也不用每周多次去银行存款。
However, eight million people in the UK still need cash, according to the Access to Cash Review, an independent body measuring the need for cash in the UK.
不过，据英国一家负责评估现金需求的独立机构“现金使用情况评估”称，英国仍有800万人离不开现金。
Those living in rural areas with poor internet connectivity and people who have physical or mental health issues are among those that find it difficult to use digital services.
其中包括居住在网络信号差的农村地区的居民，以及存在身心障碍、难以使用数字支付服务的人群。
In addition, many service providers, such as window cleaners, are still paid cash in hand.
此外，许多服务提供者，比如擦窗工，仍以现金形式收取报酬。
Not to mention, budgeting, which is easier with cash since "you know what you've got," interviewee Kev Jackson told the BBC.
更不用说用现金理财也会更简单，因为“你能清楚知道自己手头有多少钱”，受访者凯文·杰克逊在接受英国广播公司采访时表示。
Is cash dead?
现金会彻底消失吗？
Not yet it would seem, though as more technological solutions to payment, such as smart watches, become commonplace, its use is likely to decline more.
目前来看似乎还不会。不过，随着智能手表等更多支付类科技产品的普及，现金的使用量很可能会进一步下降。
What's important is, the report concludes, to put in place infrastructure to ensure that those who still need to pay the good, old-fashioned way can get their money's worth.
该报告的结论指出，至关重要的一点是，要建立完善的基础设施，确保那些仍需要使用这种传统支付方式的人群，能够享受到物有所值的服务。